In this section we are going to discuss a solution of AI agents and how it
overcome some of the challenges that we face in the case of applications built
using large language models. Okay before we get into a formal definition of
what are AI agents let's understand through a use case what is a problem
they are looking to solve. So now let's say in our use case we have an employee
named as John and he works at a corporation called as microcool and he has
worked really hard during the year and now he's looking to take a two-week
skiing vacation from mid-December if he has adequate leaps. He also needs
help with vacation planning like hotel booking, airline booking and so on. So can
a generative AI app built using large language models help John to do the
vacation planning. Now let's take a look so this is the John's ask that we saw
about. Now if you see the John's ask it's not a simple task like generating
content or summarizing content but it's a collection of tasks and decisions. So
what are the tasks and decisions? So first the application needs to check the
leave balance if he has two weeks leave then maybe research locations for
skiing check the weather port and see if it's going to snow in December, book
a flight, book a hotel and let's say he has leaves and he's able to book a
flight and everything is going good but it doesn't have adequate hotel rooms
during that duration. So it will need to make a decision and replan and ask John if
that is okay. So when you have user request which are complex in nature
requiring decision making a large language model might not be the right fit in
that scenario. Now let's take a look. Now let's say from the previous example we
just wanted to check what is the weather in New York because he was planning to
travel to New York for skiing. So what I did was I went to Anthropic and took a
look at their cloud model and ask it a question. What is the weather in New York
today and you can see it says I apologize but I cannot provide real-time weather
information because the large language model is limited by the training data
and the cutoff date. It cannot provide you current data information on
weather, flight bookings and so on. Now then I asked it another question. Can you
book a flight for me from New York to Scotland and it said I apologize but I
cannot book a flight for you directly. So I can go to these sites and book a flight
because the large language model doesn't have the tools to make an API request
to book a hotel or go to weather.com and get the weather data for you. It
doesn't have the right set of tools. Now if you'll take a look at limitations of
the large language model to a handle complex request as we saw in the last
use case. So we have the user request and we let's say we have an application
built using large language models and now let's see some of the tasks that it
cannot accomplish. So it cannot tell me about my leave balance. It can research
location for skiing because it's been trained on internet data. So it might be
able to tell me what are the locations that I can go for skiing but it cannot
check the weather report as we saw previously. It cannot book a hotel. It cannot
book a flight. So what are the challenges and limitations of large language
model-based applications? First it can provide answer to generic questions but
does not have company specific data if I want to check my leave balance. It cannot
answer questions related to current data or where external APIs are required.
Let's say if I want to know whether data book a hotel etc then it cannot also
answer questions beyond its training cut-off date. So let's say if it's
been trained in June 2024 it can answer questions post that date. Now let's see if
we have to accomplish all these tasks what do we really need to do? So one of
the limitations of the large language models connecting to maybe internal
data source we were able to overcome by building retrieval augmented generation or
rag based applications by connecting the LLMs to the internal data sources. So
now let's say we have the previous use case and we built a micro-cool
Gen AI app driven by large language models and we wanted to check the leave balance
of the employees we could connect this Gen AI app with the internal HR data
source and then retrieve the leave balance. Okay so now we were able to overcome
this challenge that John had to check the leave balance through rag based
applications but still we are not able to access the weather report book a
flight book a hotel. So all these challenges will see in the next lecture on how
agent pick based application can overcome all these challenges. That's pretty
much it from this lecture I'll see you in the next lecture thank you